- Hey, guys. Help me out.
嘿，伙计们。帮我个忙。
I need a name for my band.
我需要给我的乐队起个名字。
- Dirty Sponge?
脏海绵？
- Empty Cup.
空杯子。
- You're saying things that are in front of you.
你们在说眼前的东西。
- Girl Without a Band Name?
没有乐队名的女孩？
- That's not bad.
这不错。
That's not bad.
- Check it out, womb-mates.
看看吧，子宫里的伙伴们。
In honor of our tenth birthday,
为了庆祝我们的十岁生日，
I made a little slideshow with all our old pictures.
我做了一个小幻灯片，里面有我们所有的旧照片。
I call it, "Dawn and the Other Three."
我称之为，“Dawn和另外三个”。
- Look how young I was.
看我那时多年轻。
Didn't even have my beard back then.
那时候我连胡子都没有。
- And you don't have one now.
你现在也没有。
- Josie sees it.
Josie看到了。
Right, Josie?
对吧，Josie？
- I see some chocolate.
我看到了一些巧克力。
- A chocolate-y man-beard.
一个巧克力味的男人胡子。
- Ohh, that's a good band name!
哦，那是个好乐队名字！
- Don't look now, but I think I see
some soon-to-be ten-year-olds.
- Uh-oh! Better start saving for college.
[laughter]
Seriously, I need to get on that.
- We're just so excited
that our babies are about to turn the big ♪ One-O ♪
- ♪ We're not babies anymore ♪
- ♪ And we're in public ♪
- Anne, stop.
You're embarrassing them. [chuckles]
你在让他们难堪。[轻笑]
Now, which one of you is most excited for tonight's visit from the Quadfather?
那么，你们当中谁最期待今晚‘四胞胎之父’的来访呢？
- The what-father?
- 什么之父？
- The Quadfather.
- 四胞胎之父。
He's the mystical being that visits quadruplets
他是那个神秘的存在，会在四胞胎生日那周拜访他们
all over the world the week of their birthdays
世界各地的四胞胎都会在这一周内与他进行一次小小的会面。
for a little sit-down.
[笑]
[laughs]
你看，因为四胞胎必须共享同一个生日，
You see, because quadruplets have to share the same birthday,
四胞胎之父会分别赐予他们每个人一个特别的愿望——
the Quadfather grants each of them their own special wish--
当然，作为交换，他们会享用一顿美味的意大利餐。
in exchange, of course, for a nice Italian meal.
Then on the day of their party,
然后在他们的派对当天，
he magically appears and makes those wishes come true.
他会神奇地出现，让这些愿望成真。
- So why is he a beaver?
- 那他为什么是海狸呢？
- Oh, you are gonna love this.
- 哦，你会喜欢这个的。
- Hey, Daddy-o. Check out my jazz beard.
- 嘿，老爸。看看我的爵士胡子。
- Oh, pepper.
- 哦，胡椒粉。
[sneezes]
- （打喷嚏）
Ah! An olive.
- 啊！一颗橄榄。
When did I have olives?
- 我什么时候吃过橄榄了？
- And why didn't you chew it?
- 你为什么不嚼一嚼呢？
- I don't know.
- 我不知道。
- You guys must be super stoked the Quadfather is coming.
- 你们一定超级兴奋，因为‘四爷’要来了。
- [scoffs] Please.
- [嗤之以鼻] 拜托。
We're turning ten.
我们要满十岁了。
- Yeah, we all know it's just our Dad in a beaver suit
- 是啊，我们都知道那只是我们的爸爸穿着海狸装，
wearing an Italian suit over the beaver suit.
外面再套一件意大利西装。
- I think it's cute that he does that for you guys.
- 我觉得他为了你们这样做挺可爱的。
- It was cute, and now it's just embarrassing.
- 曾经是可爱，现在只是尴尬。
One of us has to tell him we know it's him.
我们中得有人告诉他我们知道是他。
- I vote you. - I vote Dicky.
- 我投你一票。 - 我投迪基。
- Nicky's not here.
- 尼基不在这里。
Let him tell Dad
让他告诉爸爸
we don't believe in the stupid Quadfather.
我们不相信那个愚蠢的“四方之父”。
- The Quadfather's coming!
- “四方之父”来了！
The Quadfather's coming!
“四方之父”来了！
I'm the luckiest boy in the world!
我是世界上最幸运的男孩！
- Nicky may not be the best choice.
- 尼基可能不是最佳人选。
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
♪ ♪
- [whistling melody]
- [吹口哨旋律]
♪ ♪
[rhythmic clapping] - ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
- [有节奏的拍手] - ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
- [whistling melody]
- [吹口哨旋律]
♪ ♪
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na-na ♪
- ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐呐 ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na-na ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na, na, na ♪
- ♪ 一，二 ♪ - ♪ 呐，呐，呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
- ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
- ♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
- ♪ 哦-哦，哦-哦 ♪
[classical Italian music playing]
[古典意大利音乐播放]
♪ ♪
- Uh, Nicky?
- 呃，尼基？
Before you sit down with the Quadfather,
在你和四爷坐下来之前，
there's something we have to tell you.
有些事情我们必须告诉你。
- Later. I'm making sauce here.
- 待会儿再说。我正在做酱料。
And that cheesy garlic bread is not gonna toast itself.
而且那奶酪大蒜面包不会自己烤好的。
- Nicky, we're not making anything, because the Quadfather's really--he's just--
- 尼基，我们什么都没做，因为四爷他真的——他就是——
- Say it! - Do it!
- 说出来！ - 做吧！
- He's Dad!
- 他是爸爸！
- That's ridiculous.
那太荒谬了。
Dad's not Italian,
爸爸不是意大利人，
he doesn't own a suit,
他也没有西装，
and he doesn't have the teeth of a beaver!
更没有像海狸那样的牙齿！
- The Quadfather will see you now.
‘四海之父’现在要见你。
- You can all live in your fantasy land,
你们可以活在你们的幻想世界里，
but I've got an Italian beaver to feed.
但我得去喂我的意大利海狸。
♪ ♪
- [imitating Vito Corleone] Hello, Nicholas.
（模仿维托·科里昂）你好，尼古拉斯。
I hope you brought me some pasta I can't refuse.
我希望你带了些我无法拒绝的意大利面。
- Mangia.
吃吧。
- What? No cheesy garlic bread?
什么？没有蒜蓉奶酪面包？
This displeases me.
这让我不高兴。
- It was the others.
是其他人。
They tried to convince me that you're really just...
他们试图说服我你真的只是...
[sputters] Our Dad.
我们的爸爸。
- That's radicchio!
那是菊苣！
Clearly I'm a mystical oversized beaver in an Italian suit.
显然我是一个穿着意大利西装的神秘巨型海狸。
Bring them to me.
把他们带来见我。
So...
所以...
You come to me with a wild accusation,
你带着一个荒谬的指控来找我，
and this, the week of your birthday.
而且是在你生日这一周。
- [scoffs] Really, Dad?
- [嗤之以鼻] 真的吗，爸爸？
We're still doing this?
我们还在玩这个？
- Silencio.
- 安静。
If I were your Dad,
如果我是你爸爸，
would I eat like this?
我会这样吃东西吗？
- Yes.
- 是的。
- Eh.
- 嗯。
If this is how you feel,
如果你是这么想的，
then I guess you have no special requests for me.
那么我想你对我没有什么特别的要求。
- We actually have one.
- 实际上我们有一个。
We don't want the Quadfather to make an appearance at our party.
我们不希望‘四方之父’在我们的派对上出现。
- [both gasp]
- [两人同时惊呼]
- But I always make an appearance.
- 但我总是会出现的。
- It just feels a little juvenile.
- 这感觉有点幼稚。
We're gonna be ten.
我们就要十岁了。
- Single digits are for learning.
- 个位数是用来学习的。
Double digits are for earning.
十位数是用来赚钱的。
- What does that even mean?
- 那是什么意思？
- Don't listen to them.
别听他们的。
Fresh pepper?
新鲜辣椒？
- Yeah.
嗯。
[grunting]
（咕哝声）
[sneezes]
（打喷嚏）
- That's weird.
真奇怪。
You sneeze just like...
你打喷嚏的声音就像……
- [sneezes]
（打喷嚏）
- I know it's you, Dad.
我知道是你，爸爸。
- But, Nicholas...
但是，尼古拉斯……
- You broke my heart.
你伤了我的心。
[grunts]
哼。
- Tried to tell you, dude.
我试过告诉你的，伙计。
♪ ♪
- [sighs dramatically]
（戏剧性地叹气）
- Haven't seen him like this
好久没见他这样了
since that time we forgot to tell him
自从那次我们忘记告诉他
our hide-and-seek game was over.
捉迷藏游戏已经结束了。
- That was bad.
那次真的很糟糕。
He was behind the toilet for 17 hours.
他在厕所后面躲了17个小时。
- Dad used it three times.
- 爸爸已经用了三次了。
[shudders]
[颤抖]
- We'll worry about him later.
- 我们晚点再担心他。
Right now, we've got a party to plan.
现在，我们得计划派对。
- Yeah, we need something that really says "Ten."
- 是啊，我们需要一些真正能表达“十”的东西。
[snaps fingers] What about a beach party?
[打响指] 海滩派对怎么样？
- Yeah, we'll have a party
- 对，我们会在科罗拉多众多著名的海滩之一举办派对。
on one of the many famous Colorado beaches.
- 我是说海滩主题。
- I meant a beach theme.
有沙子，头上插着兰花，手里拿着椰子饮料……
With sand, orchids in our hair, coconut drinks in our hands...
- 我讨厌沙子。它总是跑到不该去的地方。
- I hate sand. It gets in places.
What about a club party with pumpin' dance music
那来个俱乐部派对，放点劲爆的舞曲
so I can bust out a little...
这样我就可以小小地展示一下...
Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz!
咚次！咚次！咚次！咚次！咚次！咚次！咚次！咚次！
- I don't unz.
- 我不咚次。
But I do have a better idea.
但我有个更好的主意。
- What? A science party?
- 什么？科学派对？
- No.
- 不是。
A...extreme party.
一个...极限派对。
With things that are extreme.
有各种极限活动。
- More like extremely lame.
- 更像是极度无聊。
- Well, beaches are lamer.
- 嗯，海滩更无聊。
- Well, unzes are lamest. - What?
- 嗯，unz更无聊。 - 什么？
- Why do we never get to see it?
- 我们为什么从来没见过？
[all arguing over each other]
[大家互相争论]
- I am so done... - You know why?
- 我受够了... - 你知道为什么吗？
- Kids! Kids!
- 孩子们！孩子们！
Hey!
嘿！
What is this all about?
这都是怎么回事？
- Are you reconsidering having the Quadfather at your party?
- 你在考虑在你的派对上请Quadfather吗？
All: No!
所有人：不！
- It was worth a shot.
——试试也无妨。
- We're trying to plan what we want for our party.
——我们正在计划我们派对上想要的东西。
- Oh, I get it.
——哦，我明白了。
Now that you're turning ten,
——既然你就要满十岁了，
you wanna kick things up a notch.
——你想让事情更上一层楼。
Well, leave the planning to me.
——那么，把计划交给我吧。
As usual, mama's got you covered.
——一如既往，妈妈会帮你搞定的。
- Uh-oh.
——哎呀。
- I've got my fun kit packed with all my greatest hits--
——我已经准备好了我的乐趣套装，里面装满了我最棒的节目——
face painting, balloon animals,
脸部彩绘，气球动物，
and everyone's favorite singing sock puppet,
还有大家最爱的唱歌袜子木偶，
Justin Timbersock!
贾斯汀·蒂姆伯斯克！
"I'm bringing socksy back."
“我要把袜子带回来。”
- We appreciate your effort,
我们感谢你的努力，
but that stuff is so nine.
但那些东西已经过时了。
- [gasps]
（吸气声）
What is happening?
发生了什么？
- Well, it's not looking good for Justin Timbersock.
嗯，对贾斯汀·蒂姆伯斯克来说不太妙。
Nicky, how about you? How do you feel about all this?
尼基，你怎么看？你对这一切感觉如何？
- Since there is no happy in my birthday anymore,
自从我的生日再也没有快乐了，
why have a party altogether?
为什么还要一起办派对呢？
- He's right.
他说得对。
Why have a party all together?
为什么还要一起办派对呢？
We should have separate parties.
我们应该各自办派对。
- That's it. Separate parties.
没错，各自办派对。
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
等等，等等，等等。
Why have separate parties
为什么我们要分开办派对，
when we can each have our own?
而不是各自办自己的呢？
- Wow.
哇。
You've never had separate parties before.
你以前从未举办过分开派对。
But I guess if that's really important to you,
但如果这对你们真的很重要，
then...
那么...
I could plan separate parties.
我可以策划分开派对。
- Quaddle-up.
准备好了。
It was a tough decision,
这是一个艰难的决定，
but we all decided we're old enough to plan our own parties.
但我们大家都认为我们已经足够成熟，可以自己策划派对。
- Sorry, but we're growing up, Anne.
对不起，但我们正在长大，安妮。
- Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
Well, planning parties is harder than you think.
嗯，策划派对比你想象的要难。
You'll see!
你会看到的！
They'll see, right, Tom?
他们会看到的，对吧，汤姆？
- Oh, they'll see.
- 哦，他们会看到的。
They think they're so grown up.
他们以为自己已经很成熟了。
They'll see how much they need us.
他们会看到他们有多需要我们。
They'll see!
他们会看到的！
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
- Ow!
- 哎哟！
♪ ♪
- Wow.
哇。
Look at us.
看看我们。
We really pulled this off.
我们真的做到了。
- Totally crushed it.
完全碾压了。
- Left no stone unturned.
没有留下任何未尽之事。
- They didn't see.
他们没看到。
- They don't need us.
他们不需要我们。
- ♪ Mommy wanted to help ♪
♪ 妈妈想帮忙 ♪
♪ They just didn't need her ♪
♪ 他们只是不需要她 ♪
♪ Can someone please explain ♪
♪ 有人能解释一下吗 ♪
♪ Why the Quadfather's a beaver ♪
♪为什么四爸是个海狸♪
♪ Separate parties ♪
♪分开的派对♪
♪ No beaver ♪
♪没有海狸♪
♪ Separate parties, no beaver ♪
♪分开的派对，没有海狸♪
- Josie. - Sorry.
josie. - 对不起。
[clears throat]
[清喉咙]
All: Mae! Welcome to my party.
全部人: 妙！欢迎来到我的派对。
She's here for my party.
她是来参加我的派对的。
I invited her to my party.
我邀请她来参加我的派对。
- You invited me to all three parties.
- 你邀请了我参加三个派对。
[all scream]
[所有人尖叫]
[all screaming]
- ♪ Separate parties, same guests ♪
不同的派对，相同的客人
♪ Which will they choose? We don't know ♪
他们会选择哪一个？我们不知道
- [deep voice] Awkward.
尴尬
- Okay, so we left one tiny stone unturned.
好吧，我们还有一个小问题没解决
- This is a disaster.
这是一场灾难
- A delicious disaster.
这是一场美味的灾难
Both: They need me.
他们需要我
- Hup--leave it to me, beaver.
交给我吧，海狸
It's Mommy time. - Ohh.
是妈妈的时间了。 - 哦。
- Another one, Josie.
- 再来一个，Josie。
And keep 'em coming.
继续来。
- You should all come to my party.
- 你们都应该来参加我的派对。
- I've got volleyball. - I've got rock-climbing. - I've got unzes.
- 我有排球。 - 我有攀岩。 - 我有unzes。
- Looks like a party emergency.
- 看起来像是派对紧急情况。
Did somebody call 9-Mom-Mom?
有人打9-妈妈-妈妈了吗？
- Mom-no-no.
- 不-不-不。
- [shushing] It's okay.
- [嘘声] 没关系。
It's okay now.
现在没事了。
Ten years ago, I gave you life.
十年前，我给了你生命。
Today, I am gonna save it.
今天，我要拯救它。
- Mom, you need to let us handle this like adults.
妈妈，你需要让我们像成年人一样处理这件事。
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe. Catch a tiger by its toe.
一，二，三，四，抓住老虎的脚趾。
If he hollers, let it go.
如果它叫喊，就放开它。
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe.
一，二，三，四。
- Yes!
是的！
I get first pick.
我先选。
Mae.
梅。
- [scoffs] She's my best friend.
她是我最好的朋友。
- The moe gets the Mae. - Fine.
- 摸到Mae。 - 好吧。
Ashley! - Connor.
Ashley！ - Connor。
- Jordan. - Callie.
- Jordan。 - Callie。
- Charlotte. - Clay.
- Charlotte。 - Clay。
- Ryan. - Taylor.
- Ryan。 - Taylor。
- Since it's your birthday,
- 既然今天是你的生日，
you can have oddly old-looking Oscar.
你可以选那个看起来很老的Oscar。
- Hey, Oscar. Ready to party?
- 嘿，Oscar。准备好派对了吗？
- Say, you're not gonna be playing
- 说起来，你不会放那些嘻哈音乐吧？
any of that hippity-hop music, are you?
- 欢迎来到海滩，各位！我准备了一个超棒的派对。
- Welcome to the beach, people!
欢迎来到海滩，各位！
I got a jam-packed party planned.
我准备了一个内容满满的派对。
First up, team volleyball.
首先，团队排球赛。
All we need are two teams.
我们只需要两支队伍。
And we only got enough for one. Scratch volleyball.
但我们只有足够的人组成一支队伍。取消排球赛。
Uh, soccer?
呃，足球？
No.
不。
Tug-of-war.
拔河比赛。
Tug-o-no.
拔河也不行。
You know what?
你知道吗？
Skip all the team stuff.
跳过所有团队活动。
How about we limbo?
我们玩个林波舞怎么样？
Who wants to go first?
谁想先来？
- I'll go.
- 我来。
Yolo.
你只活一次（YOLO）。
Right, kids?
对吧，孩子们？
[club music playing]
[俱乐部音乐播放]
- Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz!
- 嗯嗯！嗯嗯！嗯嗯！嗯嗯！嗯嗯！嗯嗯！嗯嗯！嗯嗯！
- Um, why aren't you letting the other boys in?
- 呃，为什么不让其他男孩进来？
- 'Cause all cool clubs have a line.
- 因为所有酷炫的俱乐部都有排队。
- But this club isn't cool.
- 但这俱乐部并不酷。
- Are you crazy? There's a line outside.
- 你疯了吗？外面排着队呢。
- And always be sure to firmly tighten the--
- 而且一定要确保紧紧拧紧——
- Dude, we get it.
- 伙计，我们明白了。
It's a helmet.
这是头盔。
Now can we do something extreme?
现在我们可以做点极限运动吗？
- Of course!
- 当然可以！
Right after this extremely long safety video.
就在这个超长的安全视频之后。
- [sniffs]
- [嗅]
You catching a whiff of garlic?
你闻到大蒜味了吗？
- I am.
- 我闻到了。
I wonder if it's this garlic bulb in my pocket.
不知道是不是我口袋里的这个大蒜球。
- [hisses]
- [嘶嘶声]
It burns my vampire blood. Eh?
它让我的吸血鬼血液感到灼热。嗯？
Funny, right?
有意思，对吧？
Right?
对吧？
- Does this look like it's in the mood for jokes?
- 这看起来像是有心情开玩笑的样子吗？
- Nope.
- 不是。
You look as serious as a garlic bulb.
你看起来和大蒜球一样严肃。
What's up with that?
怎么回事？
- This is what we use to signal the Quadfather.
这是我们用来召唤‘四方之父’的信号。
When we're ready for him,
当我们准备好迎接他时，
we'd smash the garlic and he appears at our party.
我们会砸碎大蒜，他就会出现在我们的派对上。
- Nicky, you know he's not coming, right?
尼基，你知道他不会来的，对吧？
- Yeah, I know.
是的，我知道。
Might as well just throw it out.
还不如直接扔掉。
- So how's it going over here?
这里情况怎么样？
- It's been going great, Mom.
一切都很好，妈妈。
My party's been so fun, everybody needed a nap.
我的派对非常有趣，每个人都想打个盹。
It's a total snooze fest.
完全是个打瞌睡的聚会。
I don't have enough people to have any fun.
我这里人不够，玩不起来。
- Well, it is a good thing I brought my fun aid kit.
还好我带了我的欢乐补给包。
I've got just the cure.
我有解药。
[sputters noisemaker]
[吹响噪音制造器]
- I'll have a Denver omelet!
我要一份丹佛煎蛋卷！
- All right, problem solved. What's next?
好了，问题解决了。接下来呢？
Bring it.
来吧。
- Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz!
嗯！嗯！嗯！嗯！嗯！嗯！嗯！嗯！嗯！嗯！嗯！
- Now this is what I call a party.
这才叫派对嘛。
- Yo, Reggie, are you letting anyone in now?
哟，雷吉，你现在让谁进来了吗？
What are you doing here, Dawn?
你在这里做什么，Dawn？
- I want my best friend with me,
- 我想和我最好的朋友在一起，
so if you give me Mae,
所以如果你给我Mae，
I'll give you a girl from my party.
我会给你一个我派对上的女孩。
- Will that girl dance more than foot-not-loose Mae?
- 那个女孩会比脚不灵活的Mae跳得更多吗？
- Just try and stop her. - Deal.
- 试试阻止她。 - 成交。
- Call me sliced bread, 'cause this is my jam!
- 叫我切片面包，因为这是我的最爱！
- No deal! No deal! - Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz!
- 不行！不行！ - Unz！Unz！Unz！Unz！
Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz! Unz!
Unz！Unz！Unz！Unz！Unz！Unz！Unz！Unz！Unz！Unz！Unz！
- Mom!
- 妈妈！
- What's this? A test?
- 这是什么？一个测试？
- No.
- 不。
An extreme list of questions
一个极端的问题列表
that you have to answer correctly in order to fly.
你必须正确回答才能飞行。
- So a test.
- 所以是个测试。
- Well, when you put it like--
- 嗯，当你这么说——
- Bet there's no stupid test at Dawn's party.
- 我打赌Dawn的派对上没有愚蠢的测试。
- What if I drop the essay question?
- 如果我丢掉论述题怎么办？
- This is great, Mae.
- 这太棒了，Mae。
I finally got the party I wanted.
我终于得到了我想要的派对。
Who wants to play volleyball?
谁想打排球？
All: Yeah! - Whoo-hoo!
所有人: 耶！ - 哇呼！
- Dawn, I don't think there's enough room.
- 晨曦，我觉得场地不够。
- I got this, Mae.
- 我搞得定，梅。
Volley for serve!
发球！
Ow!
哎哟！
It's all good, everyone.
没事的，大家。
Not a party till someone gets hit in the face.
没人被打到脸就不算真正的派对。
- Not cool, Dawn.
- 不酷，晨曦。
- Yeah, you can't just steal guests from our parties.
- 对，你不能就这样从我们的派对上抢走客人。
- Uh, not my fault I planned a better party.
- 呃，我的派对计划得更好，这不是我的错。
- Oh, yeah? Let's see about that.
- 哦，是吗？让我们看看是不是这样。
Hey, party peeps, I just turned the fog machine up to ten.
嘿，派对伙伴们，我刚把烟雾机调到十档。
11!
十一档！
[all cheer]
[众人欢呼]
- Those are my party peeps!
- 那些是我的派对伙伴！
- They were my party peeps first.
- 他们先是我派对的人。
- Now they're all mine.
- 现在他们都是我的了。
Boom!
砰！
[high-pitched whirring]
[高频嗡嗡声]
[explosion]
[爆炸声]
[all coughing]
[所有人咳嗽]
- Boom!
- 砰！
Now they're all gone.
现在他们都消失了。
- [coughs]
- [咳嗽]
- Don't worry, everyone.
- 别担心，大家。
The extreme fun is right this way.
极致的乐趣就在这边。
Okay, who's first in the skydiving simulator?
好了，谁先来体验跳伞模拟器？
- No way.
- 不可能。
You spent 45 minutes explaining
你花了45分钟解释
all the ways you might get extremely hurt.
所有你可能会受到极度伤害的方式。
- It's perfectly safe. I'll show you.
- 绝对安全。我展示给你看。
[electronic whirring]
[电子嗡嗡声]
[thuds]
[重击声]
See that?
看到了吗？
Totally still alive.
完全还活着。
- These separate parties are weak.
- 这些分开的小派对太弱了。
- Yeah, I miss when you guys used to have one big fun party.
- 是啊，我怀念你们以前一起开一个大派对的时候。
- It's all been leading up to this, Tom.
- 这一切都是为了这一刻，汤姆。
This is not a drill.
这不是演习。
Well, this is, but...
嗯，这倒是，但是...
Mommy is gonna save the day.
妈妈会拯救这一天。
Josie, cake.
乔西，蛋糕。
This cake's gonna be a la mode.
这个蛋糕将会是时髦的。
[gasps] I'm out of ice cream.
[吸气声] 我没有冰淇淋了。
- Sweet.
甜。
And we know what happens after the cake--
我们都知道蛋糕之后会发生什么——
the Quadfather.
四重奏之父。
- Actually, no. Not this year.
实际上，不，今年不会。
- But the Quadfather's the best part.
但四重奏之父是最精彩的部分。
All: Yeah.
大家：耶。
- [sighs]
（叹气）
I wish I still had that garlic.
我真希望我还有那颗大蒜。
- Good thing I kept it for you.
还好我为你留着它。
Signal that beaver.
给那只海狸发信号。
- Thanks, toots.
谢谢，美女。
[garlic bulb crunches]
（大蒜瓣被咬碎的声音）
[blows air]
（吹气）
- [sniffing]
（嗅闻）
[whistles lightly]
（轻轻吹口哨）
- Guys, you know the Quadfather's
伙计们，你们知道四爸其实就是我们老爸穿了海狸服吧？
really just our Dad in a beaver suit, right?
是啊。但谁在乎呢？还是很有趣的。
- Yeah. But who cares? It's still fun.
对啊，他还用肉弹枪朝我们射肉丸呢。
- Yeah, he shoots meatballs at us from his meat-zooka.
好耶！
All: Yeah!
伙计们，我们现在都十岁了。
- Guys, we're ten now.
我们已经太大了，不适合再玩四爸的游戏了。我说得对吧？
We're too old for the Quadfather.
呸！
Am I right?
别呸！我们还有蛋糕呢。
All: Boo!
耶！蛋糕！蛋糕！
- No boo! We still have cake.
蛋糕！蛋糕！蛋糕！蛋糕！蛋糕！
Yay cake! Cake! Cake!
耶，蛋糕！蛋糕！蛋糕！
All: Cake! Cake! Cake! Cake! Cake!
大家：蛋糕！蛋糕！蛋糕！蛋糕！蛋糕！
[all gasp]
[所有人惊叹]
Floor cake! Floor cake! Floor cake! Floor cake!
地板蛋糕！地板蛋糕！地板蛋糕！地板蛋糕！
[all groan]
[所有人呻吟]
- First no Quadfather, and now floor cake?
首先没有Quadfather，现在又是地板蛋糕？
Worst party ever, Harpers.
这是最糟糕的派对，Harpers。
- What did the boy say?
那男孩说了什么？
- They're right.
他们是对的。
I guess we should blow out our candles.
我想我们应该吹灭蜡烛。
- What should we wish for?
我们应该许什么愿呢？
- I wish we still believed in the Quadfather.
我希望我们仍然相信Quadfather。
- He still believes in you.
他仍然相信你。
- [imitating Vito Corleone] What's this I hear? You little gabagools are leaving without a meatball?
我听说什么了？你们这些小家伙要空手离开？
- It's the Quadfather!
这是Quadfather！
Don't be fusilli!
别闹别扭了！
[laughs]
（笑）
[meat-zooka pops] [laughs]
（肉丸炮弹声）（笑）
- So that was our tenth birthday.
那是我们的十岁生日。
We all learned a little something that day.
那天我们都学到了一点东西。
- It's okay to want to grow up,
渴望成长是可以的，
but don't grow up too fast.
但不要成长得太快。
- Or you'll miss all the fun along the way.
否则你会错过沿途的所有乐趣。
- And remember, when life shoots you meatballs...
记住，当生活向你投掷肉丸时...
Wear a face mask.
戴上口罩。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- This never gets old.
这永远不会过时。
- Mom, next year you should go back to planning our party.
妈妈，明年你应该重新规划我们的派对。
- Oh, honey. I've already started.
哦，亲爱的。我已经开始了。
- [laughs]
[笑声]
- And, Nicky, thanks for saving our butts.
- 尼基，谢谢你救了我们。
- Don't thank me.
- 别谢我。
Thank the Quadfather.
谢‘四人组之父’吧。
- Boom! [laughter]
- 砰！[笑声]
- ♪ ♪
- [whistling melody]
- [吹口哨旋律]
♪ ♪
- [vocalizing]
- [发声]
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ 耶 ♪
[vocalizing]
- [发声]
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ 是的 ♪
- ♪
♪